So, you've seen the structure of the risk factor model and how it
你已经见过风险因子模型的结构
attempts to explain a portfolio's risk in terms of the common risk factors.
并且知道它如何使用公共风险因子解释投资组合的风险
Let's see how this works with a factor that we've seen before,
下面用一个我们之前见过的因子（市场收益率）举例说明
the market return which was introduced when discussing the capital asset pricing model.
我们在讨论资本资产定价模型时讨论过市场收益率
Our goal is to use the market return as a single factor in
我们的目标是将市场收益率作为
our Risk Factor Model and then fill in
风险因子模型中的单个因子
the values that we need to calculate the portfolio variance.
然后填充计算投资组合方差所需的值
First, there is the covariance matrix of factors.
首先是因子协方差矩阵
Since there's only one factor,
因为只有一个因子
it has one value which is the variance of
所以它有一个值
the market's excess return above the risk-free rate.
即高于无风险利率的市场超额收益率方差
To make our example more manageable,
为了简单起见
we'll work with just two stocks.
假设只有两支股票
For the matrix of factor exposures,
对于因子暴露度矩阵
we want the factor exposure of each stock to the single factor,
我们需要每支股票对这一个因子的暴露度
which in our model, is the market return.
在我们的模型中 这个因子是市场收益率
So the factor exposure matrix is a column vector with two rows,
因子暴露度矩阵是一个列向量 有两行
and the transpose is a row vector with two columns.
转置矩阵是一个行向量 有两列
We'll also fill in the matrix of specific returns for each stock.
还需要填充每支股票的特有收益率矩阵
Let's see how we get the values that we'll put into the matrices of this risk model.
下面看看如何获取填充到此风险模型矩阵中的值
For the variance of the market factor,
对于市场因子的方差
we can collect a time series of an index.
我们可以收集某个指数的时间序列
For instance, the S and P 500 if the stock universe is focused on the US stock market.
例如 如果股票池专注于美国股市 这个指数可以是 S&amp;P 500
We can choose a time window of four weeks,
我们可以将时间窗口设为
eight weeks, or 12 weeks.
4 个星期 8 个星期或 12 个星期
Then calculating the variance of this time series gives an estimate for this value.
计算这个时间序列的方差可以估算此值
There's a bit of a judgement call as to what time window to use.
使用什么样的时间窗口需要主观判断
Too short of a sample,
时间窗口太短的话
and the data is mostly noise.
数据噪点太多
Too long of a sample,
太长的话
and the earlier data points may no longer be
很早之前的数据点
useful for estimating the current variance of the market.
对于估算市场的当前方差可能没有帮助
Also, the time window used for analysis scales
并且 时间窗口会随着
with a holding period and the frequency at which we expect to trade.
持有期限和预期交易频率而延长
So, for daily trading,
对于每日交易
we may try different windows of several weeks.
我们可以尝试包含几周的不同窗口
For strategies with longer holding periods,
对于持有期限更长的策略
we may use a longer time window such as one,
我们可以选择更长的时间窗口
two, or three years.
例如一年 两年或三年
So now we've estimated one value in the risk model.
现在我们已经估算出风险模型中的一个值